sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
You finally came.
やっと来てくれたか。
What is the situation?
状況は？
敵は おそらく 50はいる。
I'd say there are about fifty
of the enemy.
Compared to that,
there are just four of us left alive.
それに比べ こっちの生き残りは
オレたち４人だけだ。
It'll all be over soon.
We will all attack at once.
もう少しで ケリがつく。
一気にいくぞ！
皆さん このクナイを 一斉に
敵側へ投げつけてください。
Everyone, please direct these kunai knives
towards the enemy all at once.
あとは 私一人でやります。
I will do the rest...
そんなムチャな！
いくらなんでも。
That's crazy! Not even you could...
Shut up and do as he says.
黙って 言うとおりにしろ。
これから 木ノ葉の黄色い閃光の
戦いが見られるぜ。
We're about to see
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf in battle.
一瞬だ。 見逃すなよ。
It'll happen in a flash. Don't miss it.
It's healing well...
((だいぶ よくなってる。
But don't over-exert yourself
or you'll open up the wound.
(でも あんまりムリすると
傷口 開いちゃうよ))
((オレや お前が傷ついたとき➡
When you and I were wounded,
Rin saved our lives with
her Medical Ninjutsu!
リンは いつも 医療忍術で
命を救ってくれたんだぞ！
If she hadn't been there,
we'd both be dead by now!
アイツがいなけりゃ オレもお前も
とっくに死んでたんだぞ！
Right now, saving Rin takes priority
over the mission!
(今は 任務のことより
リンを助けるほうが優先だ！))
((確かに ルールや掟は大切だが➡
Kakashi, rules and regulations
are indeed important.
それだけが すべてじゃないよ。
But that isn't everything.
Didn't I teach you...?
教えたろ。 状況に応じて➡
There are times
when the situation requires
(臨機応変に対処しなきゃ
ならないときもある))
impromptu responses
against the enemy.
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero...
((オレは 白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
確かに 忍の世界で➡
Sure in the world of ninja,
ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
those who break the rules and regulations
are regarded as scum...
But...
(けどな 仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ))
those who abandon their comrades
are worse than scum!
Kakashi Chronicles
~
A Boy's Life on the Battlefield
Part 2
~
I found them...
《見つけたぞ。
落ち着け！
オレにだって できる！》
Calm down... I can do this!
I'll take care of it.
(タイセキ)オレが 片付けてくる。
In the meantime, use your genjutsu
and get the information from her.
その間に お前は 幻術を続けて
さっさと 情報を聞き出しておけ。
Camouflage Jutsu...
迷彩隠れの術。
All right... Here I go!
よし いくぞ！
Go where?
どこへだ？
K-Kakashi... How come you're...?!
カ カカシ… お前 どうして!?
ま お前みたいな泣き虫忍者１人に
任せておけないでしょ。
Well, I can't leave this up to
a crybaby ninja like you, can I?
カカシ…。
Kakashi...
白銀の髪に
その白光のチャクラ刀…。
That silver-white hair and
White Chakra Blade...!
まさか お前…
木ノ葉の白い牙!?
Don't tell me you're...
the "White Fang" of the Leaf?!
これは 父の形見だ。
This is my father's keepsake.
((忍に必要なのは
任務に役立つ道具だ。
To carry out his mission,
useful tools are essential to a ninja.
(感情なんてのは
余計なものなんだよ))
Something like emotions are useless.
《カカシ お前…》
Kakashi... you...
I see... You're the White Fang's kid...
なるほどな。 白い牙のガキか。
なら ビビる必要はねえな。
Then there's no need to
be afraid of you.
《やっぱりな…》
I thought so.
匂いは 完全に消されてる。
The scent has been completely erased.
かすかな空気の流れや 物音で
敵の位置を判断するしかないぞ。
We'll have to locate him
by the slightest movement
and noise he makes.
ど… どこだ？
Wh-Where is he?
Obito, behind you!
オビト 後ろだ!!
ぐあっ！ 目が…。
My eye...!
Kakashi!
カカシ！
おい カカシ！ 大丈夫か!?
Hey Kakashi! Are you all right?!
Even if he's just a kid,
it doesn't hurt to be cautious...
(タイセキ)たとえ ガキ相手とはいえ
用心に こしたこたぁねぇ。
じっくりいくか。
I'll take it nice and slow.
敵のヤツ… やり手だよ。
Our enemy... He's good...
オレの血の匂いのついたクナイは
ちゃんと 捨ててやがる。
He threw away the kunai knife stained
with the smell of my blood.
また 目にゴミでも入ったのかよ。
Don't tell me you got dust
in your eye again?
忍が 泣くなっての。
A ninja shouldn't cry...
I'm not dead yet.
まだ 死んだわけじゃない。
気を抜くなよ。
Stay focused!
There's no way dust can
get into your eyes
((ゴーグルしてるのに
目に ゴミが入るわけないよね。
when you have goggles on.
自制心を口にするなら➡
If you're going to advocate self-control,
don't just mouth the words.
(口だけじゃなく
心も強くもたないと))
Act strong too.
I'm just talk...
Always being saved by others...
《オレは いつも口先だけで➡
みんなに
助けられてばっかだ。
口先だけの落ちこぼれだ。
けど…》
Just a big-mouthed loser...
But...
((オレは 白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero...
(仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ))
Those who abandon their comrades...
are worse than scum!
《あの言葉だけは 口先だけに
したくはないんだ！》
I don't want those words
to be just empty talk!
(タイセキ)死ね!!
Die!
Wh-Why...?
(タイセキ)な… なぜだ。
見えるわけはない。
There's no way you can see...
オビト… お前！
Obito... You...!
Wh-What is... that eye...?
な… なんだ。 その目は…。
This time... I'll protect my comrade!
ここは…
仲間はオレが守る！
Obito... That eye of yours...
オビト… お前その目！
ああ… これが写輪眼みてえだ。
Yeah... I guess this is the Sharingan.
チャクラの動きや流れが
目に見える。
I can now see the movement
and flow of chakra.
大丈夫か カカシ！
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
Yeah...
ああ… どうやら左目は
もう ダメそうだが➡
Looks like I lost my left eye,
リンからもらった これがある。
but I have the kit Rin gave me.
応急処置なら すぐできる。
I can use it for emergency first-aid.
すぐに リンを助けに行くぞ！
おう！
We're going to save Rin immediately!
Okay!
You're surprisingly stubborn.
意外に しぶといヤツだ。
Hmm.... They're all so pathetic.
どいつもコイツも だらしねえ。
リンの チャクラの流れが荒れてる！
The flow of Rin's chakra is disturbed...
オレや お前の
チャクラの動きと違うぞ！
It's different from your chakra
or mine.
おそらく 幻術に かけられてる…。
She's probably under a genjutsu...
すぐにでも
情報を 聞き出そうとしたんだ。
They didn't waste any time trying
to get the information out of her.
フン… どうやら
ただのガキどもじゃないようだな。
It seems they're not mere kids.
一度 手合わせしたが
かなりの早技だ！
We fought him earlier.
He's fast... Stay alert!
気をつけろ！
おう！
Right!
解！
Release!
カカシ… オビト…。
Kakashi... Obito...!
助けにきたぞ リン！
もう 大丈夫だ！
We've come to save you, Rin!
You'll be all right now.
よし！ あとは さっさと退散だ！
All right, now let's get out of here!
なるほど…
いいコンビネーションだったが➡
I see...
You two made a good team,
but you're still just kids.
しょせん ガキだな。
今 お前らのいるのは
敵の 手のなかだぜ。
Right now, you're in enemy hands.
Earth Style: Rock Breaker!
土遁！ 岩宿崩し!!
やばい！
This is bad!!
出口に走れ!!
Run for the exit!
ぐわっ！
カカシ!!
Kakashi!
Too bad, I lost a good source
of information...
せっかくの情報源だったが…➡
Oh well, it can't be helped.
まぁ しかたねえか。
くっ…。
大丈夫か？ リン… カカシ…。
Are you all right?
Rin...? Kakashi...?
(カカシ)オビト!!
Obito!
ううっ…！ くっ…!!
やめろ…。
Don't... It's okay, Kakashi.
いいんだ カカシ…。
オレは… もう ダメみたいだ…。
I don't think... I can make it...
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって…➡
My right side is totally crushed.
感覚すら… ねえ…。
I can't even feel anything...
くっ！ ハァ ハァ…。
クソ～ッ！
Dammit!
いや… そんな… どうして…。
No... This can't be... Why...?
オビト!!
Obito...!
チクショウ！ チクショウ!!
Dammit!
オレが… オレが 初めから
お前の言うとおりに➡
If... If only I had listened to you,
一緒に リンを助けにきてたら➡
and we had come to rescue Rin
in the first place...
こんなことには
ならなかったんだ～!!
This never would've happened!
なにが 隊長だ… なにが 上忍だ!!
So what if I'm a captain?!
So what if I made jonin?!
そういや… 忘れてたぜ…。
Oh yeah... I had forgotten...
オレだけ…➡
I was the only one who...
お前に 上忍祝いのプレゼント…➡
didn't give you a gift...
やってなかったな… カカシ…。
for becoming a jonin, Kakashi.
何が いいか… 考えてたんだ…。
I was... wondering what to give you...
んでよ… 今… 思いついたんだ…。
and I just had a thought.
なに… 安心しろ…。
Don't worry...
役に立たない…➡
It's not some useless, extra baggage...
よけいな… もんじゃない…。
この オレの写輪眼をやるからよ。
I'm giving you... my Sharingan.
里のヤツらが何て言おうと➡
Whatever the village may say...
お前は立派な上忍だ。
you are... a great jonin.
それがオレの気持だ。
That's how I really feel...
受け取ってくれ。
So please accept it.
リン お前の医療忍術で➡
Rin... Use your Medical Ninjutsu...
オレの写輪眼を眼軸ごと➡
Take the entire eye and transplant...
my Sharingan...
カカシの左目に移殖してくれ。
into Kakashi's left eye.
カカシ こっちに来て。
Kakashi, come over here...
I'll start it right away.
すぐ始めるから。
オレは もう死ぬ。
I'm about to... die...
けど お前の目になって➡
But... I'll become your eye and...
これから先を見てやるからよ。
see the future... for you.
しぶてえな…
まだ生きてやがったか。
How stubborn...
You're still alive, huh?
が… やっぱりガキだな。
But... you're just a kid, after all.
忍が何泣いてやがる。
What's a ninja crying for?
来な 泣き虫。 ケリつけてやるぜ。
Come on, crybaby! Let's settle this.
《あのガキ
さっきと様子が少し違うな》
That kid...
He seems different than before...
カカシ リンを頼むぜ。
Kakashi... take care of... Rin.
あぁ。
Yeah...
慌てるなよ リン。
Don't panic... Rin.
ハァ ハァ…。
カカシ リンを… リンを連れて早く➡
Kakashi... Take Rin...
Take Rin and... get out... of here.
ここを離れろ。
敵の援軍が来るぞ。
Enemy reinforcements...
will be coming.
オビト…。
Obito...
いいから行け。
It's okay... Just go...
リン！
Rin!
土遁！ 裂土転掌！
Earth Style! Earthquake Slam!
リン 早くつかまれ！
リン！
Rin, hurry, take my hand!
Rin!
オビト！
Obito!!
《カカシのヤツと➡
Just when Kakashi and I were...
starting to get along...
せっかく仲よくなれたのに➡
リンには結局➡
I couldn't tell Rin that I...
loved her...
告白できなかったなぁ…。
みんなと➡
I wish... I could've spent more time...
with everyone.
もっと一緒にいたかった…》
オビト！
Obito!
チクショウ！
Damn it...!
オビト
お前が完成させてくれた術だ。
Obito... This is the jutsu
you helped me perfect!
ほうほう こんな状況で
まだ闘う意志を見せるとは➡
Hmm... You still have the will to fight,
even in this situation?
敵地後方まで
コソコソ潜り込んでくるだけはあるな。
No wonder you were able to sneak
so deep into enemy territory.
気が強い。
You are a determined one.
リン！ コイツらはオレが足止めする。
Rin! I'll hold them off!
Get out now!
その隙に逃げろ！
でも…！
But...!
オレはオビトに お前を頼まれたんだ。
I promised Obito I'd look after you...
だから お前は死んでも守る！
I'll protect you with my life!
カカシ…。
Kakashi...
リン オビトはお前のことが
好きだったんだ。
Rin... Obito cared about you.
大好きだった 大切だった。
He loved you...
You were everything to him.
だから 命がけで守ろうとした。
That's why he gave his life
to protect you.
なら カカシ！ 私の気持だって…!!
Then, Kakashi! You should know
my feelings for you...
オレは！
I...!
オレは一度
お前を見捨てようとしたクズだ。
I tried to abandon you...
I'm nothing but scum.
行け！ リン!!
Rin, go!
オレは… 死んだのか？
Am I... dead?
ここは？
Where am I?
気がついたみたいだね。
Looks like
you've regained consciousness.
Huh?!
先生！ どうして？
Sensei! But how...?
このクナイの術式は
オレが時空間忍術で➡
The jutsu formula on this kunai knife
serves as a marker
飛び回るための目印なんだよ。
when I leap using
the Transportation Technique.
じゃあ 敵は？
Then... the enemy?
オレが全員 倒したよ。
I took them all down...
リンは？ リンはどこなんです!?
Rin...
Where is Rin?!
間に合わなくて
すまなかった カカシ。
I'm sorry
I couldn't make it in time, Kakashi...
話は全部 リンから聞いたよ。
Rin told me everything.
＜第三次忍界大戦
その長きにわたる戦いは➡
The Third Great Ninja War.
With the sacrifice of
many nameless ninja,
名も無き多くの
忍たちの犠牲によって終結した。
this long war finally came to a close.
そして 同時に名だたる英雄たち➡
In its wake, it also left legends...
語り継がれる伝説を
残したのである。
The stories of great heroes,
to be told and retold
for generations to come.
神無毘橋の戦い。
The Battle of Kannabi Bridge...
その日 木ノ葉隠れに➡
That day, two heroes were born
in the Hidden Leaf Village,
２人の写輪眼を持つ
英雄が生まれた。
each with his own Sharingan.
１人は その名を慰霊碑に刻み➡
One found his name engraved
on the memorial stone.
１人は のちに
写輪眼のカカシと呼ばれ➡
The other came to be known
as "Kakashi of the Sharingan".
他国にまで
その勇名を轟かせるのである＞
In time, the tales of his bravery spanned
all borders, and beyond.
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
(パンサーリリー)
『FAIRY TAIL』 前回までは…。
Next Episode
Capture Uchiha Itachi...
(メスト)知りたい…
あらすじというものを➡
It won't be an easy mission.
俺は知りたい。
(パンサーリリー)怪しすぎる。
(シャルル)てなわけで
Ｓ級試験に参加中のメストが➡
But it's something I can't avoid.
ギルドの者じゃないかもしれない
と思った私たちは➡
天狼島に向かったってわけ。
To bring back Sasuke, eh?
(パンサーリリー)怪しすぎる。
I'm sure you're aware of this,
(シャルル)そして島には
もっと大変な危機が➡
but Sasuke is now powerful enough
to even kill Orochimaru.
迫りつつあったの。
I know that.
But I never go back on my word.
(メスト)知りたい。
危機というものを 俺は…。
(パンサーリリー)
だから 怪しすぎるだろ！
That's my Ninja Way.
The Ones Moving Out
Next time: "The Ones Moving Out"